# Jared Coleman

jaredraycoleman.com

# SUMMARY & SKILLS

I have a broad interest in computer science. My research interests include distributed computing, internet of things (IoT), machine learning (ML), artificial intelligence (AI), blockchain, mobile robotics, discrete mathematics, computational geometry, and game theory.

Languages: Python, C/C++, Java, JavaScript

University of Southern California

Technologies/Frameworks: Docker, Tendermint, Git, React, Gitpod

**Graduate Courses**: Advanced Algorithm Design, Distributed Systems, Formal Verification, Randomized Algorithms, Theory of Computation, High-Performance Computing, Programming Languages, Operating Systems

#### **EDUCATION**

Ph.D. in Computer Science; GPA: 4.0	Aug 2020 – Present
California State University, Long Beach	Long Beach, CA
Master of Science in Computer Science; GPA: 4.0	$Aug \ 2018 - May \ 2020$
Bachelor of Science in Computer Science; GPA: 3.6	Aug~2013-May~2018

#### EXPERIENCE

The Aerospace Corporation	El Segundo, CA
Member of the Technical Staff	Mar 2020 - Present
Associate Member of the Technical Staff	$Sep \ 2018 - Mar \ 2020$
Intern	$Jan\ 2018-Aug\ 2018$

- Design software that helps Aerospace rapidly develop scalable, modular, and efficient analyses for launch vehicle verification in simulation, day-of-launch, and post-flight environments.

### CSULB Research Foundation

Long Beach, CA

Los Angeles, CA

Student Research Assistant

Mar 2017 - May 2018

- Developed software and simulations for systems of cooperative robots.

# Publications

#### DARSAN: A Decentralized Review System Suitable for NFT Marketplaces

Sulyab Thottungal Valapu, Tamoghna Sarkar, Jared Ray Coleman, Anusha Avyukt, Hugo Embrechts, Dimitri Torfs Michele Minelli, Bhaskar Krishnamachari

ICBC 2023 - International Conference on Blockchain

#### Search and Rescue on the Line

Jared Coleman, Lorand Cheng, Bhaskar Krishnamachari

SIROCCO 2023 - International Colloquium on Structural Information and Communication Complexity

# PhD Forum Abstract: Cooperative Problem-Solving with Systems of Constrained Mobile Agents Jared Ray Coleman

IPSN 2023 - International Conference on Information Processing in Sensor Networks

#### Graph Convolutional Network-based Scheduler for Distributing Computation in the IoRT

Jared Coleman, Mehrdad Kiamari, Lillian Clark, Daniel D'Souza, Bhaskar Krishnamachari MILCOM 2023 WS-7 - Workshop On The Internet Of Things For Adversarial Environments

# Delivery to Safety with Two Cooperating Robots

Jared Coleman, Evangelos Kranakis, Danny Krizanc, Oscar Morales-Ponce

SOFSEM 2023 - International Conference on Current Trends in Theory and Practice of Computer Science

#### The Snow Plow Problem: Perpetual Maintenance by Mobile Agents on the Line

Jared Coleman, Oscar Morales-Ponce

ICDCN 2023 - International Conference on Distributed Computing and Networking

# Line Search for an Oblivious Moving Target

Jared Coleman, Evangelos Kranakis, Danny Krizanc, Oscar Morales-Ponce

 $OPODIS\ 2022\ -\ International\ Conference\ on\ Principles\ of\ Distributed\ Systems$ 

# Multi-Objective Network Synthesis for Dispersed Computing in Tactical Environments

Jared Coleman, Eugenio Grippo, Bhaskar Krishnamachari, Gunjan Verma

SPIE Defense + Commercial Sensing 2022

# Network Synthesis for Tactical Environments: Scenario, Challenges, and Opportunities

Tzanis Anevlavis, Jonathan Bunton, Jared Coleman, Mine Dogan, Eugenio Grippo, Abel Souza, Christina Fragouli Bhaskar Krishnamachari, Matthew Maness, Karl Olson, Prashant Shenoy, Paulo Tabuada, Gunjan Verma SPIE Defense + Commercial Sensing 2022

# Robotic Sorting on the Grid

Jared Coleman, Oscar Morales-Ponce

ICDCN 2022 - 23rd International Conference on Distributed Computing and Networking

# Message Delivery in the Plane by Robots with Different Speeds

Jared Coleman, Evangelos Kranakis, Oscar Morales-Ponce, Danny Krizanc

SSS 2021 - 23rd International Symposium on Stabilization, Safety, and Security of Distributed Systems

# The Pony Express Communication Problem

Jared Coleman, Evangelos Kranakis, Oscar Morales-Ponce, Danny Krizanc

IWOCA 2021 - 32nd International Workshop on Combinatorial Algorithms

# Minimizing The Maximum Distance Traveled To Form Patterns With Systems of Mobile Robots

Jared Coleman, Evangelos Kranakis, Oscar Morales-Ponce, Jorge Urrutia, Birgit Vogtenhuber

CCCG 2020, 32nd Canadian Conference on Computational Geometry, August 5-7, 2020

#### PROJECTS

#### ChatLang (eclipse.usc.edu/chatlang)

An LLM-powered role-playing bot with parallel tutor assistance

2023

#### Kubishi Sentences (sentences.kubishi.com)

An LLM-powered sentence builder/translator for the Owens Valley Painte Language

2023

#### GCN-Turtlebot (github.com/ANRGUSC/gcnschedule-turtlenet)

GCN-based Scheduler for Distributing Computation in the Internet of Robotic Things

First-place winner: 2nd Student Design Competition on Networked Computing on the Edge at CPS IoT Week 2022

# Secure IIoT

Autonomous Networks Research Group & Chevron

 $Using\ blockchain\ technology\ to\ secure\ industrial\ Io\ T\ systems$ 

#### Kubishi (kubishi.com)

An online dictionary and encyclopedia for Owens Valley Paiute language and culture

2020

#### Aerocube @ The Beach

CSULB & The Aerospace Corporation

Distributed robotics systems for space - a proof of concept

2017